<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Marco Mina</title>
    <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mrcmina.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mrcmina.github.io/images/icon_huf353bb36df4d8067ac82d59651618b5a_243756_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Da Vicenza a Montreal studiando le foreste</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/ctca_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/ctca_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short article about me on the italo-canadian journal &lt;em&gt;Cittadino Canadese&lt;/em&gt; written by Giulia Verticchio / Un breve articolo sul mio percorso di ricerca all&amp;rsquo;estero e integrazione in Canada sul giornale &lt;em&gt;Cittadino Canadese&lt;/em&gt; scritto da Giulia Verticchio&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are ash trees doomed?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ash trees have been part of North American and European forest landscapes for millennia. Yet, they are now under threats from invasive pests and pathogens (ash dieback and the emerald ash borer). I report here some updated information on ash’s conservation status and their battle for survival in our landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/are-ash-trees-doomed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The challenge of managing forests for multiple ecosystem services in a changing world</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 26-28 February 2020, about 200 scientists – forest ecologists, economists, policy analysts and conservationists – as well as interested stakeholders, students and practitioners from Europe and beyond gathered together in Bonn, Germany, to discuss scientific evidence relating to the current state of ‘integrated’ forest management approaches across the globe. Here’s my attempt of a short reportage of three very dense days in the European Forest City 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EFI Resilience Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/2020/03/26/the-challenge-of-managing-forests-for-multiple-ecosystem-services-in-a-changing-world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant tree hunting and old-growth forest conservation in Vancouver Island</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Temperate rainforests are magical ecosystems. In them trees grow tall, big, massive. Big and tall trees, however, means also big, tall money. When European pioneers arrived in Eastern North America they found forests with huge trees, but it only took a few decades to get rid of ancient giants. In the Pacific Northwest, some patches of old-growth forest remain but they’ve never been more ecologically – and economically – valuable and more in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/old-growth-forests-vancouver-island/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing and managing forests as functional complex networks – an interview with Christian Messier</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2017 I participated to a very dynamic field-week that took place in Tuscany, Italy. Here international students had the chance to discuss new concepts in forest management, such as viewing forest ecosystems as complex adaptive systems. One of the organisers, Prof. Christian Messier form the University of Quebec, recently published an article proposing a novel approach for managing forested landscapes at multiple spatial scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/forests-functional-complex-networks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing forests as functional complex networks</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although a variety of forest management approaches to cope with climate change have been proposed worldwide, what has been missing so far is a way to integrate them at appropriate scales, particularly at landscape level, and to put a primary focus on enhancing forest resilience in the Anthropocene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EFI Resilience Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/2019/04/11/managing-forests-functional-complex-networks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The symmetry of competition. Does the battle take place above or below our feet?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/efi_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, I talk about the “mode of competition”, in other words whether trees of different species compete more of aboveground or belowground resources when growing in mixed stands. Additionally, I highlight the advantage of mixed forests in the context of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EFI Resilience Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/2018/10/16/the-symmetry-of-competition-does-the-battle-take-place-above-or-below-our-feet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Were forests not taken seriously enough in the last IPCC 1.5° report?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest IPCC special report discusses the potential impacts of global warming of 1.5 °C and presents several pathways scenarios but without focusing much on the need of protecting and sustainably managing the forests we currently have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/forests-ipcc-report/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The symmetry of competition. A battle crown-to-crown or roots-to-roots?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/jvs_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/jvs_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forests rich in tree species are not only known for providing higher levels of ecosystem services but also to be prompter to cope with unexpected disturbances and climatic changes. However, the mechanisms of competitions in multi-species forests are all but clear. Scientists are still puzzled about which combinations of tree species grow better in a particular environment or what factors promote or reduce a positive growth complementarity in secondary forests and/or plantations. A recently published JVS paper (Mina et al. 2018, Journal of Vegetation Science 29 775-787) tackled this question for the three economically most important species growing in Central Europe: Norway spruce (Picea abies), silver fir (Abies alba) and European beech (Fagus sylvatica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vegsciblog.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Vegetation Science Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vegsciblog.org/2018/09/15/the-symmetry-of-competition-a-battle-crown-to-crown-or-roots-to-roots/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The symmetry of competition. Does the battle take place above or below our feet?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of my previous posts I have already focused on the complex topic of competition among tree species. In that post I discussed the variability of species interactions (aka mixing effects) which depends on multiple environmental factors. Here I would like to enter even more into the specific. I would like to talk a bit about the “mode of competition”, in other words whether trees of different species compete more of aboveground or belowground resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/symmetry-competition-tree-species/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more maple syrup?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we tend to think about forests as sources of important ecosystem service. But there is a very important service that is delivered mostly by one tree species: maple syrup. Since the early 19thcentury – and even before by Native Americans – the precious sap of Sugar maple growing only in Eastern North American forests has been tapped for producing granular sweetener and syrup. However, since the tapping season is very much depended on weather conditions, scientists have started wondering whether current production could be maintained if temperature and drought events will keep increasing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/no-more-maple-syrup-climate-change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do European forest managers want to know from scientists about mixed forests?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last years, scientists published a large amount of papers and books on the ecology and functioning mixed forests. This has certainly contributed to advance our understanding of how a mixed species forest work, develop, function. Many studies focused on adapting management strategies under climate change to deliver important recommendations to practitioners. But what are the main concerns of forest managers nowadays? Are they indeed worried about climate change and natural disturbance or do they just want to know how their forest will grow and when it will be ready to cut? A consortium of scientists took this time a different perspective to get answers (or better, to get questions!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/questions_managers_mixed_forests/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching complex adaptive system science to manage forest ecosystems – an interview with Klaus Puettmann</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September is a busy month for academics. To wake up researchers after the summer break, usually many conferences and events are being organized. After the IUFRO Congress in Freiburg i.B., last September I participated to a field course that took place at the Vallombrosa Forest in Tuscany (Italy). This course brought together students from several universities and countries. It focused on teaching theoretical concepts, such as resilience and complexity theory, and how these can be practically applied in natural resource management settings. In this post I interview one of the course organizers, Prof. Klaus Puettmann from Oregon State University (OSU) to better understand why complexity science should be taught in forest management programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/management-forests-complex-systems/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What factors determine whether tree species compete or complement each other?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The growth of the forest depends on a series of variables and their complex net of interactions. When the forest is composed of multiple species (called a “mixture”) its growth also depends on the intra- and inter-specific interactions between these species. Given the rising interest for biodiversity conservation, among other ecosystem services, there have been a number of growing studies on mixing effects. In this post I would like to quickly present the main results of my newly published paper on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/mixing-effects-tree-species/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IUFRO 2017 Freiburg, Germany</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, two authors of Forest Monitor (Rafał and Marco) visited IUFRO 2017 Conference that was held in Freiburg (Germany). In this post, we would like to share with you our insights about this conference, discuss some presentations and new ideas we have seen there and what was our general impression about the congress. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/iufro-2017-freiburg-germany/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of the Forest - how trees reconquered the European continent after the last Ice Age</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People who are interested in the ecology of European forests know that the current climatic gradient has a big influence in shaping the distribution and diversity of tree species in the continent. Shrubs and evergreen broadleaves in the southern Mediterranean areas, broadleaf and mixed forests in temperate regions, conifers in north and in the Alps. However, this is just a snapshot. Forests in Europe have varied greatly over the last million years due to the alternating cycle of glacial and interglacial period. Research on this topic is carried out to better understand how trees spread back after the Ice Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/the-return-of-the-forest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aliens are coming! Threatening invasion or new opportunities from introduced tree species in Europe?</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Austrian “Apfel strudel” and the Italian “Castagnaccio” are only two of the many culinary recipes that are traditional in Europe. But did you know that their main ingredients are the product of trees – Malus domestica and Castanea sativa – that are actually non-native to Europe? Many trees and crops have been introduced to Europe over the last centuries but when does a species become “invasive”? Could newly introduced tree species be an opportunity in this uncertain era of climatic changes? Scientists are trying to make light to many of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/invasive-tree-species/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of Silver fir under climate change and browsing</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are back on the million dollar question: how will our forests develop in this uncertain era of climate change? Yes, many study showed that changing climate might have strong impacts on the dynamics of temperate forests, but let’s not forget that management and other factors played (and will play) an important role for European forests. Among the different forest ecosystems in Europe, the mixed silver fir-beech Dinaric forests are one of the most fascinating to me. Read more what researchers from University of Ljubljana and ETH Zürich found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/fir-climate-change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The response of the forest to drought - the role of stand density and species diversity</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trees are beautiful complex adaptive organisms. As we see them standing immobile, deeply rooted to the ground and unable to move, we may think that they are defenceless to any change happening to their surrounding environment. In the case of drought, trees have evolved to use different strategies for facing water stress. However, intense and repeated droughts can induce changes in carbon allocation, regeneration rates and mortality. As the frequency and intensity of droughts are expected to increase in many regions due to climate change, scientists are trying to quantify growth responses to drought and to propose adaptation strategies. Read more about what different researchers recently found on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/response-forest-drought-trees/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The growth before death - a better understanding of tree mortality using tree ring data</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the historical drought in California causing the death of something like 102 Million trees in the Sierra Nevada, the topic of tree mortality is hotter than ever. It is usually easy to see if a tree is standing dead or alive. However, understanding the physiological mechanisms that lead to tree mortality and predicting mortality patterns over space and time remains a challenge. Read more what a large pool of researchers recently found using to tree ring records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/growth-death-better-understanding-tree-mortality-using-tree-ring-data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecosystem services, mountain forests and climate change</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_00/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/post/fm_00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When speculating on what is going to happen to our forests in an uncertain future, it is hard to generalize. Impacts on tree growth, regeneration and mortality due to climate change and other factors (e.g., forest management, disturbances) are usually quantified with scenario modelling at course, large-scale. However, given the heterogeneity of European mountain forests, the effects of climate change on ecosystem services at the local-scale seems to be highly variable. Read more what researchers from ETH Zürich in collaboration with other European partners found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post is published in the website 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Forest Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forest-monitor.com/en/ecosystem-services-mountain-forests-climate-change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the link to the post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
