<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Marco Mina</title>
    <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mrcmina.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mrcmina.github.io/images/icon_huf353bb36df4d8067ac82d59651618b5a_243756_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>REDEFiNE</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/redefine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/redefine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-duration&#34;&gt;Project duration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 - ongoing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REDEFiNE: REsilience Diversity landscapE Forest NEtwork&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increasing frequency, intensity, and uncertainty of high-impact disturbance events due to global change are negatively impacting our ability to predict and manage forest growth and dynamics, therefore challenging the capacity to maintain ecological resilience and ecosystem services from forests worldwide. Forest ecosystems are complex adaptive systems, thus a multi-scale perspective and &lt;strong&gt;integrated landscape management&lt;/strong&gt; approaches are needed to manage forests under increasing socio-ecological changes. One way to make forests more resilient to future threads is to increase functional diversity and redundancy at stand scale, and to optimize functional connectivity, centrality and modularity of forest patches in large fragmented landscapes. All this requires model-based evaluations of future landscape trajectories and a detailed analysis of the forested landscape as a &lt;strong&gt;functional complex network&lt;/strong&gt;. 
This project aims at coupling &lt;strong&gt;simulation modelling&lt;/strong&gt; with methods based on &lt;strong&gt;functional diversity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;network analysis&lt;/strong&gt; to determine strategic interventions at stand and landscape scale to maximize the resilience of the forests to known and unknown disturbances with the minimum effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work with the spatially-explicit forest landscape model 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landis-ii.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LANDIS-II&lt;/a&gt;  with the physiologically-based extension 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landis-ii.org/extensions/pnet-succession&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PnET-Succession&lt;/a&gt; , upscaling biochemical processes (e.g., photosynthesis, transpiration) from stand (1 ha) to landscape scale (&amp;gt;1M ha). We model forest landscape and disturbance dynamics in southern Quebec, testing alternative forest management strategies to increase forest resilience to changing climate and disturbance regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project follows three main research steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to couple process-based models of stand- and landscape-scale of forest dynamics with functional diversity and network theory;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to evaluate multi-scale forest management options to maintain and increase resilience under scenarios of climate and global change (incl. unexpected disturbances),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to determine threshold levels of both fragmentation and functional diversity below which the overall resilience of a landscape is threatened under combinations of pulse and press disturbances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project will test novel and innovative ways to implement resilience-based forest management for large fragmented forest landscapes that are typical of temperate ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has been financed in 2018-2019 via a career funding scheme awarded to Marco Mina by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snf.ch/en/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss National Science Foundation&lt;/a&gt;  (Postdoc Mobility 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://p3.snf.ch/project-175101&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grant N. 175101&lt;/a&gt;). The project is continuing thanks to funding by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chairs-chaires.gc.ca/chairholders-titulaires/profile-eng.aspx?profileId=4449&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Canada Research Chair in Forest Resilience to Global Changes&lt;/a&gt; awarded to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cef-cfr.ca/index.php?n=Membres.ChristianMessier&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Christian Messier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;partners-and-collaborators&#34;&gt;Partners and collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cef-cfr.ca/index.php?n=Membres.NuriaAquilueJunyent&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuria Aquiluè&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Université du Québec à Montréal UQAM and Forest Sciences and Technology Centre of Catalonia CTFC, Solsona, Spain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cef-cfr.ca/index.php?n=Membres.ChristianMessier&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christian Messier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Université du Québec à Montréal UQAM and Université du Québec en Outauais ISFORT-UQO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://necmusic.edu/faculty/matthew-duveneck-phd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Duveneck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;New England Conservatory&amp;rsquo;s liberal arts&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;Harvard Forest, Petersham MA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fortin.eeb.utoronto.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marie Joseè Fortin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;University of Toronto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-publications&#34;&gt;Key publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Messier C, Duveneck M, Fortin MJ and Aquilué N (2021). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2020_ecolapp/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Network analysis can guide resilience-based management in forest landscapes under global change&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Ecological Applications. 31(1):e02221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aquilué N, Messier C, Martins KT, Dumais-Lalonde V, &lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt; (2021). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/aquilue_et-al_2021_foreco/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A simple-to-use management approach to boost forests adaptive capacity to global uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Forest Ecology and Management. 481(118692).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messier C, Bauhus J, Doyon F, Maure F, Sousa-Silva R, Nolet P, &lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Aquilué N, Fortin MJ and Puettmann K (2019). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/messier_et-al_2019_forecosy/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The functional complex network approach to foster forest resilience to global changes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Forest Ecosystems 6:21. Summarized in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/2019/04/11/managing-forests-functional-complex-networks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EFI Resilience Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWISS-SPEMIXMOD</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/spemixmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/spemixmod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-duration&#34;&gt;Project duration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016-2018 (completed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrating Species Mixtures in Tree Growth Functions for Forest Development Models in Switzerland (Swiss-SpeMixMod)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interest for &lt;strong&gt;mixed-species forests&lt;/strong&gt; has been rising during the past years. There is a broad consensus that forests with higher species diversity are likely to be more adaptable to climate change, resilient to disturbances and provider of a higher level of ecosystem services. Although several studies showed that under certain conditions mixed-species forests can be more productive than single-species stands, the representation of species interactions in empirical forest scenario models has not received much attention so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main objective of this project is to investigate methodologies for &lt;strong&gt;quantifying the effects of species mixtures&lt;/strong&gt; on tree growth along Switzerland’s environmental gradients, and to prepare this knowledge for the use in forest scenario calculations. The project comprises of three major parts: (1) a systematic, descriptive analysis of data from the Swiss National Forest Inventory (NFI) to provide an overview of the &lt;strong&gt;frequency and the distribution of pure and mixed forests in Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;; (2) quantification of &lt;strong&gt;mixing effects&lt;/strong&gt; with nonlinear mixed-effect models fitted to NFI data and their variability with climatic, edaphic, stand and site conditions, as well as with species composition, across Switzerland’s environmental gradient; (3) identification of the different &lt;strong&gt;modes of intra- and inter-specific interactions&lt;/strong&gt; using competition indices in Swiss mixed-species forests and their integration in growth functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project  advances the understanding of the effects of species mixtures on tree growth under a broad range of environmental conditions in Switzerland. Additionally, it prepares this knowledge for further development of state-of-the-art forest scenario models, which are crucial tools for estimating potential wood supply and for supporting management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has been carried out by researchers at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsl.ch/en/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Federal Institute for Forest, Snow and Landscape Research WSL&lt;/a&gt;, Birmesdorf, Switzerland. Part of the project was developed in partnership with 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inia.es/IniaPortal/verPresentacionIngles.action&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;INIA Madrid&lt;/a&gt;, Spain who hosted &lt;em&gt;Marco Mina&lt;/em&gt; for a research stay in January and May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has been supported by a grant from the Swiss State Secretariat for Education, Research and Innovation (SERI) under the framework of the COST Action FP1206 EuMIXFOR of the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;partners-and-collaborators&#34;&gt;Partners and collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsl.ch/en/employees/thuerig.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Esther Thurig&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WSL Birmensdorf&lt;/em&gt; -  project lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsl.ch/en/employees/rohnerb.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brigitte Rohner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WSL Birmensdorf&lt;/em&gt; - deputy project lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markus Huber&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WSL Birmensdorf&lt;/em&gt; - project partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsl.ch/en/employees/brang.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Brang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;WSL Birmensdorf&lt;/em&gt;  - project partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsl.ch/en/employees/nikolova.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Petia Simeonova Nikolova&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;WSL Birmensdorf&lt;/em&gt;  - project partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-publications&#34;&gt;Key publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Huber MO, Forrester DI, Thürig E, Rohner B (2018) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2018_jecol/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple factors modulate tree growth complementarity in central European mixed forests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Journal of Ecology. 106:1106–1119. Featured in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jecologyblog.com/2017/09/18/diversity-effects-in-temperate-mixed-forests-are-modulated-by-stand-and-environmental-factors/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Ecology Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Del Rio M, Huber MO, Thürig E, Rohner B (2018) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2018_jvegsci/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The symmetry of competitive interactions in mixed Norway spruce, silver fir and European beech forests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Journal of Vegetation Science. 29:775–787. Featured in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jvsavsblog.org/2018/09/15/the-symmetry-of-competition-a-battle-crown-to-crown-or-roots-to-roots/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Vegetation Science Blog&lt;/a&gt; and in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://resilience-blog.com/2018/10/16/the-symmetry-of-competition-does-the-battle-take-place-above-or-below-our-feet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EFI Resilience Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikolova, P.S.; Rohner, B.; Zell, J.; Brang, P., (2019) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0378112719302373?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tree species dynamics in Swiss forests as affected by site, stand and management: a retrospective analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Forest Ecology and Management, 448: 278-293.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARANGE</title>
      <link>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/arange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrcmina.github.io/project/arange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-duration&#34;&gt;Project duration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012-2015 (completed)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced multifunctional management of European mountain forest RANGE (ARANGE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arange-project.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced multifunctional forest management in European mountain RANGEs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; evaluated the capacity of current &lt;strong&gt;forest management regimes&lt;/strong&gt; and possible alternative future management to provide portfolios of &lt;strong&gt;ecosystem services&lt;/strong&gt; (ES) from European mountain forests. The project included a wide range of forest types in the major &lt;strong&gt;European mountain ranges&lt;/strong&gt; and seeks to develop and evaluate strategies for their &lt;strong&gt;multifunctional management&lt;/strong&gt; under risk and uncertainty due to changing climate and socio-economic conditions. To analyse conflicts and complementarities among ES from stand to landscape scale, improved models for the assessment and projection of ES as well as novel planning and decision support tools have been developed and applied to regional case studies as informed by decision makers and other stakeholders in the study regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall aims of ARANGE have been:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to investigate the potentials and limitations of current and possible future approaches to mountain forest management for providing portfolios of ES under current and future climatic and socio-economic conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to identify related risks and uncertainties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to translate the scientific state of knowledge about the efficient provision of multiple ES from mountain forests into decision support for policy makers and forest practitioners, so as to improve the robustness of planning tools in real-world decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project addressed four main &lt;strong&gt;ecosystem services&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timber production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protection against gravitational natural hazards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the role of forests in climate change mitigation via carbon sequestration as well as bioenergy production, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nature conservation and the maintenance of biodiversity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ARANGE, state-of-the-art &lt;strong&gt;models of forest dynamics&lt;/strong&gt; at stand and landscape scales have be used. The development focus of the project was on  (i) the quantitative assessment of a range of ES, and (ii) in planning and decision support tools and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARANGE has been a Collaborative Project within FP7 (Theme KBB.2011.1.2-07) funded by the European Commission. The consortium comprised in total 16 partner institutions from 11 countries and the European Forest Institute (EFI) as an international partner, coordinating institution was the Institute of Silviculture, University of Natural Resources and Life Sciences, Vienna (BOKU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My entire PhD project was embedded in ARANGE, which allowed me to collaborate with many researchers across Europe (see below). The EU project was also funding my PhD which was carried out at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fe.ethz.ch/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chair of Forest Ecology at ETH Zurich&lt;/a&gt;, Switzerland, under the supervision of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fe.ethz.ch/en/die-gruppe/people/person-detail.NDA4Mzg=.TGlzdC8zNTM3LDk0OTc0MDY5Nw==.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Harald Bugmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-partners-and-collaborators&#34;&gt;Project partners and collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fe.ethz.ch/en/die-gruppe/people/person-detail.NDA4Mzg=.TGlzdC8zNTM3LDk0OTc0MDY5Nw==.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harald Bugmann&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ETH Zurich&lt;/em&gt; - WP leader in ARANGE and PhD supervisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6561-1943&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maxime Cailleret&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ETH Zurich now at INRAE Aix-en-Provence, France&lt;/em&gt; - PhD co-supervisor and co-author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dmartinbenito.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dario Martin-Benito&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ETH Zurich now at INIA Madrid, Spain&lt;/em&gt; - collaborator and co-author in a chapter of my PhD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unbc.ca/che-elkin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Che Elkin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ETH Zurich now at University of Northern British Columbia&lt;/em&gt; - project partner and co-author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://zaposleni.bf.uni-lj.si/en/personel/matija-klopcic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matija Klopčič&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;University of Ljubljana, Slovenia&lt;/em&gt; - project partner and co-author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Florian_Irauschek&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Florian Irauschek&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;BOKU Vienna, now at the Austrian Research Centre for Forests, Austria&lt;/em&gt; - project partner and co-author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3684-4662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thomas Cordonnier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;INRAE Grenoble, France&lt;/em&gt; - project partner and co-author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forschung.boku.ac.at/fis/suchen.person_uebersicht?sprache_in=en&amp;amp;menue_id_in=101&amp;amp;id_in=159&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manfred J. Lexer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;BOKU Vienna, Austria&lt;/em&gt; - ARANGE coordinator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-publications&#34;&gt;Key publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Bugmann H, Cordonnier T, Irauschek F, Klopcic M, Pardos M, Cailleret M. (2017). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2017_jappeco/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Future ecosystem services from European mountain forests under climate change&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Journal of Applied Ecology, 54(2), 389–401.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Martin-Benito D, Bugmann H, Cailleret M. (2016). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2016_agrformet/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forward modeling of tree-ring width improves simulation of forest growth responses to drought&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Agricultural and Forest Meteorology, 221, 13–33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Bugmann H, Klopcic M, Cailleret M. (2017). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_et-al_2017_reec/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accurate modeling of harvesting is key for projecting future forest dynamics: a case study in the Slovenian mountains&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Regional Environmental Change, 17(1), 49–64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klopčič M, &lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Bugmann H, Boncina A. (2017). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/klopcic_et-al_2017_ejfr/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The prospects of silver fir (Abies alba Mill.) and Norway spruce (Picea abies (L.) Karst) in mixed mountain forests under various management strategies, climate change and high browsing pressure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. European Journal of Forest Research, 136(5–6), 1071–1090.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irauschek F, Barka I, Bugmann H, Courbaud B, Elkin C, Hlásny T, Klopcic M, &lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Rammer W, Lexer MJ. (2021) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/irauschek_et-al_2021_ecolmod/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evaluating five forest models using multi-decadal inventory data from mountain forests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Ecological Modelling, 445, 109493.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mina M&lt;/strong&gt;, Bugmann H, (2013). 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mrcmina.github.io/publication/mina_bugmann_2013/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARANGE D2.1 - Improved and tested forest models for case study regions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Project deliverable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
